<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Klebstoff</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Klebstoff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright 2021 Krzysztof J. Czarnecki. Fair use permitted with authorship attribution. Commercial use disallowed without explicit permission.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:28:34 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kjczarne.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About Me</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:28:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a Software Developer at Technica Engineering GmbH with a focus on process automation, continuous integration systems and infrastructure tooling. I am currently involved in projects related to the automation of hardware testing in the automotive domain. I speak Python, C#, F#, TypeScript and to a lesser degree Rust. I despise C++.
My original domain is Biotechnology with focus on Genetics and Epigenetics. I have a B.Sc. degree in Biotechnology and am an alumnus of Data Science Retreat Deep Learning Bootcamp.</description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 1</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:28:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-1/</guid><description>Sin number 1: Do not modify builtins and globals This is one of the biggest no-nos for me and something that I shot myself in the foot at least twice in my career as a Python dev. I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen this used in actual production code that was deployed to some important clients.
Whence the temptation? builtins is a collection of objects that are available from within any Python script and are loaded before any script is executed by the interpreter.</description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Intro</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 22:28:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-intro/</guid><description>Seven Sins of Python - intro Python is not only the most popular programming language (according to TIOBE as of 2021) but also one of the simplest to work with and easiest to learn. Python is great for a wide range of applications from web development through command line tools to large-scale automation and deep learning projects.
It is far from the snappiest programming languages in terms of performance, however many other languages can be used alongside Python when performance is of essence.</description></item></channel></rss>