<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>work-advice on Klebstoff</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/tags/work-advice/</link><description>Recent content in work-advice on Klebstoff</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright 2021 Krzysztof J. Czarnecki. Fair use permitted with authorship attribution. Commercial use disallowed without explicit permission. Some links in blog articles are affiliate links when noted.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 23:15:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kjczarne.github.io/tags/work-advice/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I used Vim for 3 weeks. Here's how it went</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/2022-07-04-i-used-vim-for-3-weeks.-heres-how-it-went/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 23:15:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/2022-07-04-i-used-vim-for-3-weeks.-heres-how-it-went/</guid><description>I have recently had a few days off from work due to festivities in Germany and I used some of my spare time to finally investigate the Vim editor.
For those who do not know Vim is a text editor, which was developed by Bram Moolenaar and released for the first time in 1991. So it&amp;rsquo;s not that old yet. But if you consider the fact that this is an improved version of Billy Joy&amp;rsquo;s vi editor which was originally developed in 1976 for the UNIX operating system, things start to get interesting as you realize for how long it&amp;rsquo;s been around and you&amp;rsquo;ve lived merrily without ever trying it.</description></item><item><title>The Most Important Piece of Advice</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/2021-12-18-the-most-important-piece-of-advice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:59:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/2021-12-18-the-most-important-piece-of-advice/</guid><description>If were to read only one post from this blog and ignore all the others, here is a piece of advice that I would like to give to everyone who wants to vastly improve their career.
👉 The most priceless thing that will help you excel in anything you do is your brain. The second most priceless thing is your second brain.
What I mean by that?
If you are able to build a robust reference system with a very short lookup time for any possible piece of information, you will excel at everything you do.</description></item></channel></rss>