<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Chris</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/</link><description>Recent content on Chris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Chris J. Czarnecki. Fair use permitted with authorship attribution. Commercial use disallowed without explicit permission. Some links in blog articles are affiliate links when noted.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:32:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Plate Ellipse Fitting</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/plate-ellipse-fitting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 20:32:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/plate-ellipse-fitting/</guid><description>Abstract Ellipse estimation is an important topic in food image processing because it can be leveraged to parameterize plates and bowls, which in turn can be used to estimate camera view angles and food portion sizes. Automatically detecting the elliptical rim of plates and bowls and estimating their ellipse parameters for data &amp;ldquo;in-the-wild&amp;rdquo; is challenging: diverse camera angles and plate shapes could have been used for capture, noisy background, multiple non-uniform plates and bowls in the image could be present.</description></item><item><title>How Much You Ate</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/how-much-you-ate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2024 14:25:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/papers/how-much-you-ate/</guid><description>Abstract Monitoring dietary intake is a crucial aspect of promoting healthy living. In recent years, advances in computer vision technology have facilitated dietary intake monitoring through the use of images and depth cameras. However, the current state-of-the-art image-based food portion estimation algorithms assume that users take images of their meals one or two times, which can be inconvenient and fail to capture food items that are not visible from a top-down perspective, such as ingredients submerged in a stew.</description></item></channel></rss>