<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Chris</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Chris</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; 2024 Chris J. Czarnecki. Fair use permitted with authorship attribution. Commercial use disallowed without explicit permission. Some links in blog articles are affiliate links when noted.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 23:15:34 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I used Vim for 3 weeks. Here's how it went</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/i-used-vim-for-3-weeks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 23:15:34 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/i-used-vim-for-3-weeks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have recently had a few days off from work due to festivities in Germany and I used some of my spare time to finally investigate the Vim editor.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those who do not know Vim is a text editor, which was developed by Bram Moolenaar and released for the first time in 1991. So it&amp;rsquo;s not that old yet. But if you consider the fact that this is an improved version of Billy Joy&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>vi&lt;/code> editor which was originally developed in 1976 for the UNIX operating system, things start to get interesting as you realize for how long it&amp;rsquo;s been around and you&amp;rsquo;ve lived merrily without ever trying it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 7</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 22:01:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-7/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-7-from-nightmare-import-">Sin number 7: &lt;code>from nightmare import *&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking long about which sin to name as the last in the grand seven of Python No-Nos. It finally came to me when working on one of legacy projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been contributing to (sadly this one is not open-source, so I cannot share the details).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>star&lt;/em> imports -&amp;gt; imports formed like the titular &lt;code>from nightmare import *&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Star imports are tempting because they seem to reduce boilerplate. For example, instead of importing a number of objects from a module by importing them explicitly, you could just use a &lt;code>*&lt;/code> and all available objects would be imported:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 6</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-6/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 20:16:32 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-6/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-6-packaging-not-done-right">Sin number 6: Packaging not done right&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Packaging Python projects properly can be truly a pain in the neck. However learning how to properly set up a package is extremely valuable because adherence to standards means more people can use your package efficiently.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>👉 The biggest sin of all things package-related is storing Python projects as simple collections of directories.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Python is a simple scripting lanugage so the natural tendency newcomers have is to simply create folders with a bunch of scripts and then run those folders one by one. They tend to skip thinking about how &lt;code>pip install&lt;/code> is able to seemingly magically conjure foreign code out of nothingness and when they start reading on it, they claim it&amp;rsquo;s too much work to set it up properly.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Forget New Year's Resolutions, do this instead</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/forget-new-years-resolutions-do-this-instead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 16:53:35 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/forget-new-years-resolutions-do-this-instead/</guid><description>&lt;p>A while ago I had a brainwave when reading about the Agile Software Development best practices. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently found this idea somewhere in my todo lists and decided to finally give it a try, especially given the fact that my new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions never worked for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>👉 The idea: forget new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions, write user stories for your life instead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Before I go in-depth on why I think you should write something akin to user stories for your life plans, since it&amp;rsquo;s barely the beginning of January 2022 let&amp;rsquo;s look at why new year&amp;rsquo;s resolutions are not the way to go (at least in my opinion).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 5</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 23:43:52 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-5/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-5-global-destruction">Sin number 5: &lt;code>global&lt;/code> destruction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Every time I am asked about &lt;code>global&lt;/code> keyword in Python, I get a split-second heart attack. Personally I think it is one of the most unnecessary and dangerous keywords that Python has to offer. I will go one step further and postulate that if you&amp;rsquo;re using &lt;code>nonlocal&lt;/code> you&amp;rsquo;re probably doing it wrong.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>👉 The essence of this problem is misunderstanding the purpose or the mechanics of &lt;strong>scope&lt;/strong> in Python.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 4</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-4/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 20:46:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-4/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-4-exception-frenzy">Sin number 4: Exception frenzy&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Python&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>Exception&lt;/code> class is probably one of the most abused and misused features of the language. It&amp;rsquo;s also something that no developer can escape from.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>An &lt;code>Exception&lt;/code> is a pretty natural element of any language. In all languages one will always have some need for a runtime error. In case of Python, most runtime errors inherit from the &lt;code>Exception&lt;/code> class. Though technically not a base class (for that would be &lt;code>BaseException&lt;/code>), it should be treated like a base class and it often isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>C++ is the new COBOL</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/c++-is-the-new-cobol/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 22:34:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/c++-is-the-new-cobol/</guid><description>&lt;p>C++ is a great language. As much as I hate it I cannot ignore how important it is and how much it brought to the table in it&amp;rsquo;s 36 years of existence. I have tremendous respect for Bjarne Stroustrup for creating the so-called &lt;em>C with classes&lt;/em> and I personally think that it&amp;rsquo;s one of the best things that happened in programming language designs around the time when it came to existence.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Most Important Piece of Advice</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/the-most-important-piece-of-advice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 01:59:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/the-most-important-piece-of-advice/</guid><description>&lt;p>If were to read only one post from this blog and ignore all the others, here is a piece of advice that I would like to give to everyone who wants to vastly improve their career.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>👉 The most priceless thing that will help you excel in anything you do is your brain. The second most priceless thing is &lt;strong>your second brain&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>What I mean by that?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 3</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 22:26:21 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-3/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-3-unconditional-romance-with-ducktyping">Sin number 3: Unconditional romance with ducktyping&lt;/h2>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Python is truly awesome. In C++17 there is no easy way of expressing ranges. In Python an integer range \(\langle 0, 4 \rangle\) is simply &lt;code>range(0, 5)&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The syntactic simplicity and high conciseness of the language was originally related to the fact that Python does not have static typing. In Python &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Duck_typing">ducktyping&lt;/a> means that you can actually call a function that expects an integer with a string and you will likely only realize at runtime, since there is no compilation step. It makes coding in Python, well&amp;hellip; very easy to begin with but it comes at a huge cost of bugs appearing in production code.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 2</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 23:51:37 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-2/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-2-too-few-optimized-functions-used">Sin number 2: too few optimized functions used&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This one is pretty common especially for newcomers who have learnt enough about Python to be able to loop over data structures but haven&amp;rsquo;t yet realized how slow Python loops really are.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re fresh to Python, the temptation to create &lt;code>for&lt;/code> loops everywhere for lists and dictionaries is immense. Consider a fairly simple example, where we loop over 100000 random integers and we apply a simple mathematical operation to each of those integers. The most straightforward solution would be:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Sin 1</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 23:28:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-sin-1/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="sin-number-1-do-not-modify-builtins-and-globals">Sin number 1: Do not modify &lt;code>builtins&lt;/code> and &lt;code>globals&lt;/code>&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is one of the biggest no-nos for me and something that I shot myself in the foot at least twice in my career as a Python dev. I&amp;rsquo;ve also seen this used in actual production code that was deployed to some important clients.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="whence-the-temptation">Whence the temptation?&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>builtins&lt;/code> is a collection of objects that are available from within any Python script and are loaded before any script is executed by the interpreter. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used &lt;code>int&lt;/code>, &lt;code>bytes&lt;/code>, &lt;code>dict&lt;/code>, &lt;code>list&lt;/code>, etc. then these all come from &lt;code>builtins&lt;/code>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>globals&lt;/code> is a collection of objects that exist in current global scope, so objects accessible to any module at a particular point in time when your script is running.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>👉 It is tempting to modify the &lt;code>builtins&lt;/code> to expose a particular custom function or object globally to any running Python script without the need to &lt;code>import&lt;/code> a module explicitly. Likewise the modification of &lt;code>globals&lt;/code> can enable such magic as dynamic imports of modules that are a part of the same package without actually using the explicit module names.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seven Sins of Python - Intro</title><link>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-intro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 22:28:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>http://kjczarne.github.io/posts/seven-sins-of-python-intro/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="seven-sins-of-python---intro">Seven Sins of Python - intro&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Python is not only the most popular programming language (according to TIOBE as of 2021) but also one of the simplest to work with and easiest to learn. Python is great for a wide range of applications from web development through command line tools to large-scale automation and deep learning projects.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is far from the snappiest programming languages in terms of performance, however many other languages can be used alongside Python when performance is of essence.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>